Lucas Cartaxo

Back-end specialist developer

Rua Zuma de Sá Fernandes, 323 06213-140 Osasco - SP, Brazil

+55 11 998 425 000 🕓

lucascartaxo@live.com

lucascartaxo 🖸

PROFILE

Full stack devops with over 10 years of experience. I've been working for more than eight years with web development and six focused on back end. Always in a great mood, I communicate clearly and didactically. I am self-taught and curious. I believe in transparency, inspection and adaptation. I am very analytical and can be very persuasive. I always try to be organized, especially with my time.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Bionexo Senior Developer + Chapter Leader

FEV 2019 - JAN 2020

- Full stack development of acquisition, supply and management of processes of health applications
- Ecosystem composed of more than 10 microservices in RoR 5 and 6, Golang, React and other legacy applications in Java and Spring
- Develop app for planning, agreement of terms and inventory control, logistics, control of surgical processes, among others
- Queuing and messaging with SQS/SNS
- Infra as code with Terraform, Jenkins and Docker. APM, metrics and scalability of multiple applications
- Chapter leader of almost 80 developers. Social class awareness, lectures, dojos and workshops about good practices and knowledge sharing

Enjoei :P Senior Developer + DevOps

SET 2016 - JAN 2018

- Back end development for online thrift shop application
- Develop and maintenance of back-end services and REST APIs with RoR
- Leader of the infrastructure team for a couple months
- Develop CI and CD with Jenkins and Ansible
- Orchestration of containers with Docker and EC2
- Analysis, monitoring and improvement of performance at application and infrastructure level
- Design and develop complex caching systems with AWS Elasticache

Digital Pages Full Stack Developer

JUN 2015 - SET 2016

- Develop and maintenance of multi-platform e-reading systems using RoR, HTML5/CSS3, EmberJS and Node Webkit
- Work on educational areas, e-learning systems, LMS and adaptive learning
- Contact with AWS S3, EC2 and Redshift
- Complex authentication systems, SSO and integration of login systems
- Deployment control, machine orchestration and DevOps services
- BI, complex reports and data analytics

SKILLS

Ruby/RoR	
HTML/CSS	
TDD/BDD	
JS/ES6	
SQL-like	
Bash/shell	
Docker/K8S	
Agile/SCRUM	
NodeJS	
Java/Android	
AWS/Cloud	
C/C++	
PHP	
Python	
Golang	
Elixir	

LANGUAGES

Portuguese	
English	
Spanish	

EDUCATION

Faculdade de Tecnologia de São Paulo

JAN 2010 - DEZ 2012 Bachelor of Technology Game Development

Colégio Singular

JAN 2007 - DEZ 2009 Information Technology

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCES

Frankfurt, Porto and D'Ouro

FEV 2015

I lived in the city of Porto in Portugal for a month, being immersed in European culture and improving my foreign languages.

Bay Area & Silicon Valley

ABR 2014

I was part of a large project for a client using EmberJS and integration with Java Web Service with Android and iOS applications.

TechCrunch Disrupt San Francisco

SET 2012

I presented pitches from start ups to entrepreneurs and investors in Silicon Valley. Contact with representatives of American and international companies.